As a content creator, there
is one thing that you really want,
and even though you
know it won't really benefit your life,
it makes you feel good when it happens,
and
that thing is gaining followers and/or
subscribers.
There is one hill
that I'm willing to die on,
and I actually expect a lot of you to
disagree with me, and that is fine.
Some of you will think it works
and something that you should do in every
single
video, and maybe others of you
are a bit more sparing with it.
For me, it's something I will never do.
I will never tell my mentees to do it,
and it's something
that I'm about to ask you
to stop doing, and that thing
is asking for follows.
Let's rewind to how and why this
is something that's only really become
prevalent
in the last few years thanks to TikTok.
TikTok came along
and changed social media forever.
Quickly as a tangent,
we need to understand what
is known as the TikTokification of
social media. So basically, rewind to
when I started on social media.
Unless someone followed you,
they wouldn't see your posts.
We only really had feed posts,
and growth would be getting a shout-out,
someone
sharing you to their story,
and maybe word of mouth.
Then TikTok came along,
and it changed pretty much everything
forever.
TikTok's algorithm meant that you
were served content on what you liked
and what
you were interested in,
not who you followed.
Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook,
Instagram Reels, YouTube,
and YouTube Shorts, these
all work on the algorithm of content
that you're interested in.
This means that for you,
the lucky whippersnapper watching this,
your life is
easier to grow your social media platform
than anyone else before.
These platforms are working day
and night to put your content in front of
people
that are right for it,
as long as there's one thing,
you make the content good
enough.
So now that content creators know this,
they know that a large amount of
people who are going to watch
and engage with their content
are being served it, so
they think it's their perfect opportunity
to ask for a follow, to beg for a
follow. To say, "Please,
please follow me." Imagine I'm 25,
single, I'm on a night out,
and I catch eyes with a beautiful young
lady, reach
out, and we start to get on. I think,
"My God, this lady's perfect." I'm
daydreaming about a life together in the
future.
I'm thinking about how incredible she is.
Then she comes back from the toilet,
sits down next to me,
looks me in the eyes and
says, "Please take me home.
Please." I'm like, "Whoa, things
are going pretty well.
I probably would've asked you to come home
with me, but the fact that you begged me
to do it puts me off." I interviewed Seán
Casey, an Irish lad who's probably one of
the most successful ever to use social
media,
and he's a big advocate of asking for
follows,
and he has a bigger following than me.
And when I asked him about it,
he constructively said to me, "James,
I do it
because it works."
And I can't argue with that.
And I'm not saying that I'm right
and he's wrong, but my point is this, you
shouldn't have to ask. Last week I
was interviewed,
and something that's becoming a
bit of a common occurrence in this space
is that the hosts of podcasts, when we get
off air,
will kind of ask me for a bit of
information. "James, what would you do?
How could you help me out?" He said he
was trying to grow his email list, and we
spoke about all the kind of different ways
that you could grow and structure it,
and he asked about incentive structures
for getting sign-ups.
He said that he thought about giving
people a free mug if they signed up to his
newsletter. And I said,
"Do you know what the problem
is with that?" I said,
"You'll just have people on your email
list that wanted a free mug." So let's
break
down people that watch your content into
two subsets of personality traits.
Those that saw your video and went,
"Fuck me, that was so good.
I'm going to need to follow this person to
ensure I get served more of their stuff.
I'm also going to support them with a
follow." The follow
is a weird support system
vanity metric because you're judged on it,
and as shallow as humanity is, the more
followers you have, the easier it
is to get girls because of status.
And that's why people buy fake followers.
I was going to say, the easier it
is to get your dick sucked,
but I thought I'd be
a bit more professional.
If people actually unfollow you as a sign
of showing that
they no longer support you in your
endeavors, then you have people
that support you
but don't want to see your content
anymore, so they mute you, and this
is your
friends and what your family do.
They don't want to do you dirty behind
subscribing,
so they've no doubt just muted you.
Then the second group of people
that watch your content is those
that thought,
"Yeah, nice,"
then went on about their day.
And the issue with these lot is there
are some of
these that probably would follow you
if you asked them nicely, or you did that
pathetic, "And if you followed me,
you'd already know that." Give it a break,
mate. Here's the real issue
that I have with these beggy little
pathetic creator
please follow me trends. One,
it breaks the rhythm.
So we need to start the piece of content
with a well-thought-out hook, a reason for
them to stay and engage.
We then need some kind of setup,
letting them know what's
to come. We build them up,
and then just as the suspense
is getting too much, we
can pay them off.
Then we can't just piss around for too
long, and they'll just
leave.
Better to leave them wanting more than
giving them too much, but that's
another video altogether.
To beg for a follow in this position just
ruins it.
I've seen people even try to segment their
ask for a follow between the hook and
the setup. Let me tell you this,
every single person watching your content
is
looking for a reason to leave,
and the moment that you give them that
reason and you break the momentum,
they're gone.
My sensei, Ed Lawrence,
said something which is so true,
especially on YouTube.
People who have not seen your content
before hate your fucking guts, and
if you can
make content to win those people over,
you will do well.
But begging for a follow that early on
is just ruining the rhythm you've worked
so
hard for. You can try too hard.
Sometimes less is more.
Don't ruin the rhythm.
I don't recall Quentin Tarantino popping
up in the middle of
one of his films asking for a fucking
five-star review on Rotten Tomatoes
because
if the film is good enough,
they will review it anyway. Number two,
it's desperate.
Another controversial take
is you shouldn't do sales calls.
And I've done videos on this and whatever.
But although they do work,
it can be to your detriment because you
should only
really do sales calls
when you're fucking desperate for sales.
And even then,
you don't want to send people to your
calendar because when I see
that little Johnny can take calls all day,
every day, it makes me realize
little Johnny is pretty empty. And
if he's empty, maybe it's bad luck,
or maybe he's fucking shit at his job.
Some people aren't put off by that,
but I am.
You want to position yourself as someone
that's just putting out incredible content
to generate goodwill with strangers,
not just to pump your socials.
I'm at 1.4 million on Insta,
1.1 million on Facebook,
1.8 million on TikTok,
and nearly half a million on YouTube
combined without ever fucking asking for a
follow. Could I have more followers
if I asked? Probably.
But I'd feel like a right nonce for doing
so.
I'd rather have an audience of people
that didn't need to be begged to be part
of
my audience. Those who watch my content,
they'll either keep watching until they
follow, or they won't. And keep in mind,
trends that we see at present, especially
on YouTube, is this,
as long as you watch a channel,
whether you subscribe or not,
it will keep serving you the video because
YouTube knows if you watch a certain
channel,
it would be fucking stupid to stop serving
you that channel.
And it's the same on every platform.
I've actually noticed some channels where
I see less when I subscribe to them, and
I don't know what the fuckery that is.
I don't know.
But let's look at my third reason because
I could literally sit here all day
talking about this. Number three,
easy come, easy go.
If you had to beg someone to join,
they'll probably be one of the first to
leave.
Now,
when we look at the psychological bias for
something called loss aversion,
this fucks you. For any of you
that don't know,
loss aversion simply put is this.
Imagine zero is how you feel right now.
Anything additional from that
is happiness.
Anything below that is unhappiness.
If you found a $50 note on the floor,
you'd experience about a plus five, and it
would be short-lived.
We have a lot of data backing up the
notion that human beings
experience double the effect of a loss as
they do from a gain.
So in that same situation,
it would be a minus 10 if you lost $50,
and it would no doubt ruin your day.
Same amount of cash.
So if you beg for easy marginal followers,
when they leave, which they probably
will if you're not a perfect fit for them,
it will make you feel like shit when in
a week's time that person unfollows you.
You take it to heart
and wonder why on Earth you're putting out
this amazing
content and people aren't following you.
You'll doubt your purpose, your content,
your business, and your ability to produce
content. Your confidence
is a finite energy
that you need to protect.
Even this video right now,
I swear I say exactly what I want because
I only want
people that think, "Fuck me sideways
and call me Mary.
This is my guy for social media advice."
I've not once begged for a follower or a
subscriber here because it just cheapens
what I do.
At time of filming on this channel,
I have 8,620 subscribers.
If they all buy my program in the next six
months, I earn
$17.24 million. To try
and pump the metrics for
vanity would just suck in shit leads.
If I need to ask you to subscribe,
you're not right for me.
Sure,
I'll reference a link in my description,
but ultimately, I'm here to do one
thing,
and that is to help you run a better
social media
strategy.
There are millions of better coaches than
me that never made
millions.
There are way better authors than me
that sold less books, and there are
probably way better businesses going broke
because they don't understand how to
play the game.
So don't focus on begging for follows.
Focus on playing the game right.
The better your content is, the
more people that will see it.
And the more people that see it,
the more goodwill
you accrue across large amounts of people.
And a small percentage of those people
will always want to do business with you.
That's how the game works. So get to
fucking work. I couldn't give a fuck
if you subscribe or not, because if you've
made it this far in the video,
YouTube will show you my next video
anyway.
Please subscribe. Please subscribe.
Fuck off.